公元517年
The year is 517 A.D.,
史称黑暗时代
known as the Dark Ages
而名字的来由显而易见
and for fucking good reason.
一场人类军队与黑暗生物之间
An endless war between the armies of man
永无休止的战争
and the creatures of darkness
席卷了英国
has raged across Britain.
为了报复人类对黑暗生物的不公之举
And in retribution for man's injustices to creatures,
永生不死的女巫薇薇安·妮缪
the immortal witch Vivienne Nimue
传播了致命的瘟疫
had spread her deadly plague
威胁要把人类从地球上彻底消灭
threatening to wipe mankind off the face of the Earth.
彭德尔山
公元517年
于是在彭德尔山上  一棵古老的橡树下
And so at Pendle Hill, beneath an ancient oak tree,
亚瑟王  没错  就是那个亚瑟王
King Arthur... Yes, that King Arthur,
和他法术高强的巫师梅林
and his powerful wizard Merlin,
被迫向血皇后妮缪投降
were forced to surrender to Nimue, the Queen of Blood.
看看这是谁
Well, well, well.
伟大的亚瑟王驾临彭德尔山
The great King Arthur comes to Pendle Hill.
然而  带着深信人类与怪物
However, believing man and monster
永远也无法和睦共处的想法
were never meant to live in harmony,
亚瑟偷袭了妮缪
Arthur ambushed Nimue.
而她最信任的女巫戈内达背叛了她
Betrayed by her most trusted witch, Ganeida.
凡人的兵器伤不了我
No mortal weapon can harm me.
-王者之剑  -这可不是凡人的兵器
- Excalibur! - This is no mortal weapon.
盛怒之下
Pissed off,
妮缪释放了致命的瘟疫
Nimue unleashed her deadly plague.
不
No!
轻轻一挥
With one swing
传说中的王者之剑
of his legendary sword,
亚瑟砍下了血皇后之首
Arthur severed the Blood Queen's head.
即便如此  也无法阻止她
But even that wasn't enough to stop her.
所以他将血皇后砍碎
So he had her cut up into pieces,
并将每一块都分别锁在不同的棺材里
each one locked in a separate casket.
一切尚未结束  我永生永世都要复仇
This is not over. I am vengeance eternal!
不
No!
神圣的祷告者将其封印
Sealed with a holy prayer.
只有圣徒的言语才能打破这道圣印
Only the words from a man of God may break this holy seal.
随后  亚瑟命令其最勇敢的骑士们骑马离去
Arthur then ordered his bravest knights to ride off
将她邪恶的残骸埋葬在大地尽头
and bury her wretched remains in the far reaches of the land,
没有人能找到的地方
where no one would ever find her.
即使是魔鬼本尊也无济于事
Not even the devil himself.
地狱男爵
我是认真的  儿子
I mean it, son.
不准喝酒  不准打架  不要挑事
No drinking, no fighting, don't cause a scene.
提华纳
今时今日
爸  别紧张  我又不是第一次来提华纳
Relax, Dad. It's not my first time in Tijuana.
你以为我为什么要跟你说这些
Why do you think I'm telling you all this?
鲁伊兹是我朋友  我只是想把他带回来
Ruiz is my friend. I just wanna bring him back.
鲁伊兹探员不是你朋友
Agent Ruiz is not your friend.
他只是你的一个酒友
He's someone you get drunk with.
三周前
Three weeks ago,
我们派鲁伊兹探去调查一个吸血鬼巢穴
we sent Ruiz to investigate a nest of vampires.
自那之后  他就没消息了
We haven't heard from him since.
交给我
I'm on it.
我收到可靠消息  知道在哪能找到他
A reliable source told me where I can find him.
找到他就打给我
Call me when you have him.
我不会打给你的
I'm not going to call you.
打给我  这是个简单的寻人任务
Just call me! It's a simple extraction.
带鲁伊兹离开那里
Get Ruiz out of there
说声再见就闪人  别又把事情搞大了
and bid adios without making a big mess. Again.
交给我  爸
I got this, Dad!
爸
你知道我的  我很温柔
You know me, I have a gentle touch.
该死  又坏了
Shit! Not again.
摔跤
坎马卓兹  坎马卓兹  坎马卓兹
Camazotz! Camazotz! Camazotz!
今晚我们请来了一位名人
世上最伟大的超自然现象调查员
地狱男爵
我们打一场  不死不休
鲁伊兹  埃斯特班  是你吗
Ruiz! Esteban, is that you?
埃斯特班  我不是他了  我是坎马卓兹
坎马卓兹  坎马卓兹  坎马卓兹  坎马卓兹
Camazotz! Camazotz! Camazotz! Camazotz!
坎马卓兹  坎马卓兹
Camazotz! Camazotz!
坎马卓兹是什么鬼
What's up with the Camazotz crap, huh?
超自然调查防御局派你来这里
The B.P.R.D. sends you down here,
调查一个吸血鬼巢穴
investigate a nest of vampires
但是你三周前失联了
and you went silent about three weeks ago.
我想你了  伙计
I miss you, man.
别闹了  我是来带你回去的
Come on, I'm here to bring you back in.
来吧  兄弟  我们走
Come on, buddy, let's go.
那就来带我回去吧
So come on, bring me in.
对打  对打  对打
好吧
Okay.
上吧  恶魔
野兽去死
好吧  你是怎么了
Okay. Hey, what happened to you, man?
你这是什么打扮
What's with the get-up, huh?
我在训练
训练  训练什么
Training? Training for what?
为了杀你
To kill you!
好吧  帮我拿着
Okay. Hang on to that for me.
紫色很适合你
You look good in purple.
好疼
Ouch!
玩够了吧
It's been a lot of fun.
我们能走了吗
Can we get out of here?
他们对你做了什么
What did they do to you?
鲁伊兹  我们去喝杯酒好好聊聊
Ruiz! Let's have a drink and talk about this!
你是个好探员
You're a good agent!
兄弟  别这样  你不记得了吗
Buddy, come on. Come on, don't you remember?
我们在后院  坐在门廊喝啤酒
Backyards? Drinking beers on the porch?
我们还一起弹过吉他呢
We used to play guitar, man!
虽然你弹的都是不插电的嬉皮士垃圾
You-you'd play all that hippy acoustic crap
而我弹的才叫音乐
and I'd play real music.
去你妈的
To hell with this!
对不起  伙计
I'm sorry, man.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
别这样  我不想弄伤你  搭档
Come on, I don't wanna hurt you, partner.
我知道你还没有完全迷失  回应我一下
I know you're in there somewhere. Talk to me.
你喜欢扮英雄
You play the hero,
但我知道面具之下你的真面目
but I really know what is under your mask.
是吗  那我们就揭开你的面具看看吧
Oh, yeah? Is that so? Let's see what's under yours.
鲁伊兹  别闹了
Ruiz! Stop this!
不  不
No! No!
鲁伊兹
Ruiz.
我认识你  阿努·恩·罗摩
I know you... Anung un Rama.
你的心因愤怒而跳动
Your heart beats with rage.
我知道你最终会选择哪一边
I know which side you'll choose at the end.
对不起
I'm sorry.
对不起  我不是故意的  我...
I'm sorry, I didn't mean... I...
终结即将来临...
没关系  小家伙
That's okay, little guy.
你只是生性如此
You're just doing what you're doing.
我不会怪你的
I'm not judging.
地狱男爵
Hellboy.
不  我是乔什
No, it's Josh.
我经常被人认错
People confuse us all the time.
来吧  我们得走了
Come on, we gotta go.
你是怎么找到我的
How did you find me?
推特  你可算不上低调
Twitter. You don't exactly blend.
鲁伊兹的事我很遗憾  但我们得带你回去
Look, sorry about Ruiz, but we gotta take you back.
你们可以试试
You can try!
别这样  大块头  别激动
Come on, big guy. Easy.
我们只是奉命行事
We're just following orders.
他想要你回去
He wants you back.
是老头派你们来的
The old man sent you?
他只跟我们说事关重要
All he told us is its important.
我们得走了
We need to go.
朋友
再给我拿一瓶
他们买单
They're buying.
科罗拉多州
超自然调查防御局
弗吉尼亚·佩恩
维克托·凯斯特勒
埃斯特班·鲁伊兹
超自然调查防御局
墨西哥的悲剧事件
Details are still emerging
仍不断有细节浮出水面
with regard to the tragic events in Mexico.
关于地狱男爵  以及他效力的
There's very little information known about Hellboy
神秘机构  我们知之甚少
or the secretive agency that apparently he works for.
你漏了一块  我来吧
You missed a spot. May I?
爸
Dad.
我父亲常说
My father used to say
刮胡子是一天之中最重要的事
shaving was the most important part of a day.
这是绅士和非利士人的区别
Separated the gentlemen from the Philistines.
爱琴海中的岛民
只有真男人才会每天拿着刀
It takes a real man to hold a blade
抵在自己的喉咙上
against his own throat every day
却不割断颈静脉
and not cut the jugular.
布鲁姆爷爷
Grandpa Bruttenholm,
他心中尽是泰迪熊和彩虹
he was all teddy bears and rainbows.
他是个冥顽不灵的混蛋
He was an unrepentant asshole,
但是他教会了我怎么刮胡子
but he taught me how to shave.
有其父必有其子
Like father, like son.
在龙舌兰酒里烂醉三周
Drowning in tequila for three weeks
也许能暂时麻痹伤痛
may temporarily numb the pain.
但其实只会加剧你的悲伤
All it ever really does is exacerbate your sorrows
恶化你的肝脏
and the state of your liver.
我知道鲁伊兹探员的事让你很难过
I know you're upset about Agent Ruiz,
但这份工作就是这样
but it's part of the job.
大家都明白这一点
Everyone here knows that.
是我杀了他  不是工作
Job didn't kill him, I did.
我在圣母瓜达卢佩教堂边上
And I buried him 16 feet under the earth
把他埋在了十六英尺深的地下
right by the chapel of the Virgin Guadalupe,
为了能让他安息
just to make it proper.
他变成了邪恶的吸血鬼
He had become unholy, a vampyre,
无可救药的黑暗生物
a creature of darkness beyond salvation.
A creature of darkness beyond salvation?
你是说不是每个人都能像我一样偶尔
You mean, we don't all just deserve a little gentle horn shave
-磨一磨角吗  -你不一样
- every now and then? - You're different.
你一直都与众不同
You always have been.
如果我的脸能说话  一定会反对你
If my face could talk, it would disagree with you.
我认为你的脸很帅气
I think it's a beautiful face.
终结即将来临  什么终结
The end is coming. The end of what?
我不知道  这是鲁伊兹的临终遗言
I don't know. Those were Ruiz's last words.
还有什么阿努·恩...
That and something about Anung nun...
你有印象吗
Does it ring any bells?
没  世界末日的胡言乱语
Nah. Apocalyptic mutterings.
好了  真是帅气逼人
Now there... Don't you look handsome!
我相信你的话  老爸
I'm gonna take your word for that, Pops.
话说  你为什么叫我回来
Why'd you bring me back, anyway?
别说是因为你想我了
Don't tell me it's 'cause you miss me.
你还记得俄赛里斯会社吗
Do you recall the Osiris Club?
记得  泽西岛的脱衣舞俱乐部
Yeah. Strip joint in Jersey.
不是  另一个
No, the other one.
太阳神厄里奥皮克兄弟协会的资深成员
The British occult society formed in 1866
在1866年成立的英国秘会
by the ranking members of the Heliopic Brotherhood of Ra.
太阳神  我在阴间见过太阳神一次
Ra? I met Ra once in the underworld.
他喜欢近距离和人说话
He's a close-talker.
和我们一样  他们也对抗黑暗势力
You know, like us, they fight against the forces of darkness
我们的组织之间有长期的合作关系
and our organizations have a long-standing relationship.
他们是我的老朋友
They're old friends of mine.
他们想请你帮忙解决一个巨大的问题
And they've requested your assistance with a giant problem.
-是吗  什么问题  -巨人
- Oh, yeah? What's that? - Giants.
地狱男爵剥夺了我可能拥有的生活
Hellboy stole the life I might've had.
把我放逐到这个悲惨的境地
Banished me into an existence of misery.
现在我活着就是为了杀他
I now only live to kill him.
我也遭受过地狱男爵的摧残
I too have suffered at Hellboy's hands,
所以我了解你的痛苦
so I know your pain.
我感同身受  所以我召唤你前来
I felt yours, so I summoned you here.
我会带你去找一位女巫  薇薇安·妮缪
I will guide you to a witch, Vivienne Nimue,
虽然被砍碎  但她还活着并持机等待
cut to pieces but alive and waiting.
复原她
Restore her!
她会让你再次强大起来
She will make you powerful again
这样你就能复仇了
so you can have your vengeance.
-谢谢你  -过程会很艰难
- I thank you. - This is not going to be easy.
也许如此
Maybe not.
但是为了恢复力量  我能做到
But to be whole again, I can do it.
去吧
Go now.
我不明白  这事对你有什么好处
I don't get it. What's in it for you?
这就不用你操心了  野兽
That is no concern of yours, beast!
最终  我自有安排
In the end, I'll have my way
而地狱男爵将会付出代价
and Hellboy will pay what he owes.
英国
俄赛里斯会社
您的客人到了  阁下
Your guest, m'lord.
地狱男爵  欢迎  我是亚当·格拉伦勋爵
Hellboy, welcome. Lord Adam Glaren.
请容我为你介绍我的同僚
And may I introduce my associates,
艾德文·卡普博士和奥古斯特·斯温
Dr. Edwin Carp and August Swain.
你们好  你们去过泽西岛的俄赛里斯俱乐部吗
Hi. You guys ever been to the Osiris Club in Jersey?
和这里差不多  不过那里有脱衣舞女郎
It's like this, but just with strippers.
我可以摸吗
May I?
有何特别之处吗
Does it do anything special?
嗯  砸起东西来得心应手
Yeah, it smashes things real good.
我们很高兴你接受了我们的邀请
We are so very glad you accepted our invitation.
我没得可选
Wasn't really my choice.
是的  教授让你来的
Yes. The Professor.
我和你父亲是老相识了
Your father and I go back a long way.
我有所耳闻
Yeah, I heard.
俄赛里斯会社一直致力于保存
The Osiris Club has been long dedicated to preserving
大不列颠的秘史
the secret history of Great Britain.
对于像你这样的人  会社为我们
It affords us certain insights
提供了独到的见解
into individuals such as yourself.
我们有时也会向你们超自然调查防御局
We've also given vital counsel
提供重要的建议
to your B.P.R.D. on occasion.
听着  我们别废话了好吗
Look, maybe we could just get on with it.
除非你们让我飞越了半个地球
Unless you flew me halfway around the world
只是为了给我上一堂历史课
just so that we could, uh, have a little history lesson.
或许我们应该直接展示给你看
Perhaps we should just show you.
暗门
Secret door.
巨人曾经统治过不列颠群岛
Giants once dominated the British Isles.
一群邪恶的  令人作呕的生物
Vile, loathsome creatures.
既可能看你一眼  又可能一口吃掉你
As likely to eat you as look at you.
它们一直都是个麻烦
They've always been a problem.
整个英国到处都埋着他们的尸体
Bodies buried all over England.
巨人有一个古怪的特点
It's a curious feature of giants
他们偶尔会从坟墓中爬出来
that they occasionally rise from their graves
大肆破坏
and wreak havoc.
这种时候  我们就会组织一场狩猎
And when they do, we organize a hunt.
欧洲民间神话  超自然的猎人在野外追逐猎物
通常预示着灾难
-狂猎  -好名字
- The wild hunt. - Oh, catchy.
我还以为我的头就够大了
And I thought I had a big head.
显然你们在这方面是老鸟了
Clearly, you guys are old pros at this.
为什么还要我来帮你们杀一个巨人
Why do you need me to help you kill a giant?
实际上是三个
Three giants, actually.
一个  我们没问题  甚至两个也能对付
One, we can handle, perhaps even two.
但是三个加在一起  就是另外一回事了
But three, that's a different matter altogether.
这个特殊的三人组
This particular trio
威胁着新森林地区[英国南部]is terrorizing the New Forest.
吮吸那些不幸与之
Sucking on the bones of anyone
发生冲突的人的骨头
unlucky enough to fall foul of them.
要知道  他们对骨髓欲罢不能
The marrow, you see. They can't get enough.
如果有巨人到达人口密集的地方
So, if any were to reach a population center...
那就好玩了
It's Miller time.
这不是轻而易举的任务  地狱男爵
This is not a task to be taken lightly, Hellboy.
这些是巨人僵尸  非常难搞
These are Gigantum Mortis. Very unpleasant.
问你父亲就知道了
Just ask your father.
崔沃也曾受邀加入狩猎
Trevor was a guest of the hunt,
我们在1943年合力干掉了一个巨人
when we took one down in '43.
我早就知道我爸老得很慢  但是你们...
I always knew Dad aged well, but you guys...
照片就像是昨天拍的一样
Picture looks like it was taken yesterday.
这是有原因的
There's a reason for that.
你刚才准确地观察到的现象
The phenomenon you so rightly observed
源自于一场降神会
was the byproduct of a seance
我们四个人  还有你父亲布鲁姆教授
the four of us, along with your Professor Broom,
都参与了
were involved in
就在战争爆发前
just before the war.
请容我介绍我们的常驻先知
Allow me to introduce our resident seer,
伊丽莎白·哈顿夫人
Lady Elizabeth Hatton.
那天晚上我接触到的灵魂
The spirit I made contact with that night
异常地强大
was exceptionally powerful.
它警告我们有东西即将出现
It warned us that something was coming.
可能会终结人类的东西
Something that would end mankind.
而我们被选中去寻找并摧毁它
And that we'd been chosen to seek it out and destroy it.
自那之后  我们以蜗牛的速度缓慢衰老
Ever since, we've aged at a snail's pace
就是为了完成那个使命
in order to fulfill that mission
无论要耗费多久
no matter how long it took.
好吧  你们担心的这个东西
Okay. And this thing you're worried about,
它出现了吗
did it show up?
是的
Oh, yes.
你出现了
You did.
你来到这个世界的那晚  我就在现场
I was there the night that you came into the world.
那时第二次世界大战已接近尾声
World War II was coming to an end.
德国几乎被击败了
Germany was all but defeated.
但是纳粹还藏了最后一手
But the Nazis still had one last trick up their sleeve.
他们求助于臭名昭著的
They turned to the infamous
死灵法师格里戈里·拉斯普京
necromancer Grigori Rasputin.
在苏格兰海岸外的一个小岛上
On an island off the coast of Scotland,
他们聚在一起进行古老的神秘仪式
they gathered to invoke an ancient occult ritual...
想要把战局扭转成对德国有利的局面
intended to turn the tide of war back in Germany's favor.
但是出了差错
But something went wrong.
仪式没有完全按照他们的计划进行
The ritual didn't turn out quite as they planned.
杀了他
幸运的是
Fortunately,
传奇纳粹猎人  龙虾队长赶到了
legendary Nazi hunter the Lobster arrived...
你们好
Guten Tag!
带领盟军进行了大胆的突袭
leading the allies on a daring raid.
再见
Goodbye.
来吧  让魔鬼知道是谁杀了你
Here, so the devil knows who sent you.
去你的
至于你们这些踢正步的混蛋
As for the rest of you goose-stepping bastards,
小心我的热能手套
beware of my claw
因为我是来将你们所有人
for I have come to inflict justice
绳之以法的
on all of you.
布鲁姆教授和我
Professor Broom and myself
当时在和盟军合作
were working with the allies at the time.
凭借他对神秘仪式的了解
With his knowledge of the occult
以及我预见未来的天赋
and my gift of foresight,
我们率领秘密任务到达岛上
we led a secret mission to the island
准备杀死那晚从地狱深处召唤出来的
to kill whatever abomination was summoned
任何可憎之物
from the depths of hell that night.
等一下
Hold it!
接下来交给我
I'll take it from here.
但是我们发现了你
Instead, we found you.
你父亲从没跟你提起过  对吗
Your father never told you, did he?
那晚他究竟为什么在那里
Why he was really there that night?
他一定是忘说了
Must've slipped his mind.
拉斯普京把你作为武器带到了这个世界
Rasputin brought you in the world as a weapon.
怀着耐心和理解
With patience and understanding,
布鲁姆把那件武器变成了行善的利器
Broom turned that weapon into a force for good.
"耐心和理解"
"Patience and understanding."
你确定我们说的是同一个人吗
You sure we're talking about the same guy?
他在你身上看到了我们其他人看不到的东西
He saw something in you that the rest of us could not.
他把你当自己的儿子养大
And he raised you as his own son.
你应该休息一下  地狱男爵
You should get some rest, Hellboy.
黎明时集合狩猎
The hunt will assemble at dawn.
所以我不仅是恶魔之子  还是纳粹
So I'm devil spawn and a Nazi.
好极了  多谢  爸
Great. Thanks, Dad.
爸
拜托
Come on!
圣赛巴斯蒂安修道院
请尊重我们的静默誓言
这么晚不会是访客
别开门
它在哪儿  修道士
Where is it, monk?
过来  你们这些混蛋
Come here, you fucking bastards!
过来  你们敢吗
Come here! Have you got it?
我很好奇  尖叫算不算打破你们的静默誓言
I wonder, does screaming break your vow of silence, brother?
你知道我在找什么  它在哪儿
You know what I'm looking for. Where is it?
带我去
Show me!
快点
Come on!
过来  修道士
Come here, monk!
我他妈讨厌铁
I fuckin' hate iron!
打开它  念咒语
Open it. Speak the words.
你知道只有圣徒的言语
You know only the words from a man of God
才能打破这道封印
can break the seal.
快他妈打开
Fucking open it!
难道什么事都得我自己做吗
Have I gotta do everything meself?
蠢货
Gobshite.
[咒语]
欢迎回来  陛下
Welcome back, Your Majesty.
怎么  我们是去讨糖果还是狩猎巨人
What, are we trick-or-treating or hunting giants?
这是传统  向以前勇敢的猎人致敬
Tradition. To honor the brave huntsmen who've come before.
那这些长刺刀呢
And the pig stickers?
另一个传统
Another tradition.
古往今来被巨人杀手所使用
Used by giant slayers throughout the ages.
当然也经过了现代技术的改造
With a few modern modifications, of course.
比电椅的威力强五倍
Five times as potent as an electric chair.
提醒你一下  这不足以杀死巨人  但是
Not enough to kill a giant, mind you. But, uh, still,
可以轻易制服那些生物  你想要一个吗
quite handy in subduing the creatures. Would you care for one?
不用了  我有自己的传统
It's all right, I got traditions of my own.
天哪  我不用戴帽子吧
Oh, God. I don't have to wear the hat, do I?
不用  我们很清楚
No. We're very well aware
你对头上的角很抵触
of your distaste for horns.
不过作为狩猎大师  戴上这件头饰
It's my honor, as master of the hunt,
是我的荣幸
to wear the headdress.
最后是这个  暗影
And here we are. Long Shadow.
你们没有吉普车或摩托车之类的吗
Don't you have a jeep or a motorcycle or something?
那可不太公平  不是吗
That wouldn't be very sporting now, would it?
他会安全带你回来的
He'll bring you home safely.
事先声明  这不是我的主意
For the record, this wasn't my idea.
和哈顿夫人预言的一样  有三组踪迹
Three sets of tracks. Just as Lady Hatton foretold.
我数到四具尸体  虽然是残骸
I count four bodies. Parts of them, anyway.
-他们会回来的  -你为什么这么肯定
- They'll be back. - What makes you so sure?
巨人是不会留下食物的
Giants don't leave food behind.
踪迹向北  朝河的方向去了
The tracks are heading north, toward the river.
我们要在这里战斗
This is where we'll make our stand.
他们会从桥上过河
They'll use the bridge to cross.
我们可以在任意一边的灌木丛中占据位置
We can take up positions in the brush on either side.
嗯  看起来是个偷袭的绝佳地点
Yeah, seems like a perfect spot for an ambush.
我也这么想
My thoughts exactly.
-我们上  -干掉他
- Let's get him! - Take him!
快追
After him!
打倒他
Bring him down!
你真的觉得我们需要你的帮助
Did you really think we needed your help
才能去杀我们猎杀了几个世纪的巨人吗
to kill something we've been hunting for centuries?
我们决不允许魔鬼
We will never allow the devil
坐上英格兰的王座
to sit on the throne of England.
那将引发世界末日
It would usher in the apocalypse.
我必须承认
I must confess
当哈顿夫人第一次告诉我
when Lady Hatton first told me
她对未来的预见和必须做的事的时候
about her vision and what needed to be done
我有些犹豫
I was hesitant.
布鲁姆对你的潜力很有信心
Broom was so certain of your potential
并且你做了很多善事
and you have done so much good.
但是命运是变幻无常的野兽
But fate is a fickle beast.
而现在我必须做
And now I must do
你父亲多年前就该做的事
what your father should have done those many years ago.
不
No.
你的头颅将成为我们陈列室的一大亮点
If it's any consolation, your head will make
也许这能让你略感安慰
a wonderful addition to our gallery.
吉尔
Jill!
你完蛋了
You are going down!
我以为是同一个脚趾
I thought it was the same toe.
你想象不到我杀了多少人才拿到这个
You have no idea how many I had to kill.
我很快就能让你玩上"扭扭乐"
I'll have you playing Twister in no time.
抱歉  玩笑开得太早
Sorry, too soon.
你的努力很快就会得到回报
And soon you shall reap the reward for your efforts.
我不知道你会不会觉得饿
I didn't know if you'd be hungry or what, you know.
要是我在箱子里待一千年  肯定饿疯了
A thousand years in a box and I'd be starving.
你不会相信现在的人都会
You wouldn't believe what people
乱扔些什么东西  饼干
throw away these days. Cookie!
复仇是我唯一需要的食物
Revenge is the only sustenance I require.
看看这个
Look at this.
一个饱受战争和贫穷蹂躏的世界
A world ravaged by war and poverty
被无能的恐惧贩子的领导着
led by feckless fear mongers.
他们用歌唱比赛取代了剑
They've replaced swords with singing competitions.
他们时日无多了
Well, not for much longer.
我的另一条手臂呢
What about my other hand?
你确定能找回来吗
You're certain you can retrieve it?
当然  当然了
Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
然后你会遵守承诺复原我
And you'll restore me, as you promised?
别担心  你会得到应得的
Don't worry, you'll get what's due.
好事会降临在耐心等待的人身上
All good things come to those who wait.
把最后一个箱子给我  让我再次完整
Bring me the last box. Make me whole again.
然后我们将一起
And together,
用鲜血为这个世界洗礼
we will baptize this world in blood.
真疼  好了
That hurt. Okay.
看看这个
Well, look at that.
看来你们还是需要我的帮助的
I guess you did need my help after all.
等一下
Wait a minute.
我以为有三个巨人
I thought there was supposed to be three.
天哪  明天早上我肯定浑身酸痛
God, I'm gonna feel that in the morning.
到爸爸这儿来
Come to papa.
别动  帅哥
Hold still, handsome!
里面真他妈湿
It's fucking wet in there!
哥们
Pal!
你都吃了什么
What have you been eating?
该死  我忘了
Shit, I forgot.
只剩你和我了  公主
Yeah, it's just you and me now, princess!
是我的滴滴吗
Is that my Uber?
他在那儿
There he is.
-就是他  -带他上车
- That's him. - Let's get him.
欢迎回到人间
Welcome back to the land of the living.
几乎没留下伤痕  你愈合得真快
Hardly a scratch left. You heal fast.
我在哪儿
Where am I?
培根  鸡蛋和血肠  吃吗
Bacon, eggs and black pudding, do ya?
看起来你需要一顿像样的英式早餐
You look like you could use a proper English breakfast.
来吧  在你倒下之前坐下
Go on, sit down before you fall down.
我是怎么来的
How did I get here?
一个人和一辆车
A man with a van.
实际上是四个人
Actually, four men.
顺便说一下  你欠我三百镑
You owe me 300 quid, by the way.
不好意思  我认识你吗
I'm sorry, do I know you?
"提防闪电巨龙  我的孩子"
"Beware the Jabberwock, my son!"
出自英国作家刘易斯·卡罗尔的小说
《爱丽丝镜中世界奇遇记》
"口能撕咬"
"The jaws that bite,"
"爪能扼杀"
"the claws that catch!"
-"提防啾啾怪鸟"  -"啾啾怪鸟"
- "Beware the Jubjub bird," - "The Jubjub bird..."
-"躲避那狂暴的"  -"狂暴的"
- "and shun the frumious..." - "The frumious..."
"凶恶猛兽"
"Bandersnatch!"
爱丽丝
Alice.
小爱丽丝·莫纳汉
Little Alice Monaghan.
没那么小的爱丽丝·莫纳汉
Not so little Alice Monaghan.
你现在是干这个吗  用茶叶占卜
This is what you do now, huh? You what, you read tea leaves?
给别人算命吗
You, uh, you tell people's fortune?
我是在利用与生俱来的天赋
I make use of the gifts I was given.
是吗  你帮人们和死去的亲戚交流吗
Oh, yeah? You let folks talk to their dead relatives?
怎么收费  五块钱一次吗
For what, like five bucks a pop?
差不多十块吧
More like a tenner.
少撕了一个
Missed one.
糟糕
Bollocks!
你得避开烧焦的部分吃了
You'll have to eat around the burnt bits.
而且算你走运
And lucky for you, too.
占卜
手相解读  10英镑
灵命解读  20英镑
塔罗牌  30英镑
水晶球解读  30英镑
如果不是死者帮忙  我根本找不到你
If it weren't for the dead, I never would've found you.
他们一直絮絮叨叨  特别是妈妈和爸爸
They keep blathering on. Especially Mom and Dad.
对了  他们向你问好
They say hi, by the way.
爸爸  妈妈
抱歉  我不知道
Sorry. I didn't know.
你怎么可能知道呢
Why would you?
如果你有那么一点点在乎
Maybe if you'd given a flying fig
在过去的二十年里能联系我一次的话
and checked in on me once in the past 20...
什么
What?
不  他没有  我来处理就好
No, he doesn't. Just let me deal with it.
更多死者吗
More dead people?
我跟你说过  他们从不闭嘴
I told you, they never shut up.
他们现在在跟你说什么
What are they telling you now?
他们说我应该抓住机会杀了你
They're saying I should kill you while I have the chance.
你看  他们知道你不知道的事
You see, they know what you don't,
比如桌子下面有一把霰弹枪
that I've got a shotgun under the table
填装了天使之骨的子弹
loaded with angel bones
正瞄准你的裆部
aimed right at your todger.
这年头似乎大家都想要我的命
Seems like everybody wants me dead nowadays.
他们告诉你为什么了吗
They give you a reason?
只说了末日即将降临
Only that the end is coming.
而且让末日降临的人是你
And it'll be you that brings it.
谷歌翻译一下  可以吗
Google-translate that, would you?
只是几句...
It's just something that...
一个朋友告诉我的话
a friend told me, you know.
就像是预言
Like a prophecy.
恶魔
你到底开不开枪
You gonna shoot me or what?
死者可能会害怕你这个恶魔
The dead might be afraid of your demon ass,
但我更了解你
but I know you better.
再说  我还欠你一个人情
Besides, I still owe you one
你在我小时候救过我的命
for saving my life when I was just a kid.
那我们到桌子底下干什么
So, what are we doing down here?
躲开玻璃
Avoiding the glass.
武装警察
Armed police!
待在这儿
Stay here!
天啊
Jesus Christ!
我儿子真厉害
That's my boy.
爸
Dad!
你好  儿子
Hello, son.
我只是不明白你为什么这么生我的气
I just don't know why you were so angry with me.
你就不能敲门吗
You couldn't have knocked?
我告诉你了  我们清理完
Well, I told you, after we cleaned up
你和巨人战斗留下的一团糟
the mess you left behind with the giants
你又不在现场  我担心你遭遇了不测
and you weren't there, I feared the worst.
谢天谢地你没事  好吗
Thank God you're all right. Okay?
你知道比背后挨刀更让人受伤的是什么吗
You know what hurts worse than being stabbed in the back?
就是背后挨刀
Being stabbed in the back.
得了吧  你不能相信
Come on. You can't possibly believe
我早知道俄赛里斯会社密谋要暗杀你
that I knew the Osiris Club was plotting to assassinate you.
你知道我不能相信什么吗
You know what I can't believe?
我不能相信你那么多年前为了杀我
I can't believe you showed up on Nazi island
出现在纳粹人的岛上
all those years ago just to kill me.
是的  没错
Yeah, that's right,
我碰见了你的老情人  哈顿夫人
I bumped into your old flame, Lady Hatton.
她给我补充了一些
She, uh, filled me in on a couple of
我们的家庭故事中的遗漏之处
the missing pieces of our family narrative.
如果你想挖我的陈年旧事
Well, if you wanna dig up my sordid skeletons,
我会第一个坦诚相告
I'll be the first to hand you a shovel.
但现在不是时候
But this is not the time,
而且我想介绍你认识一个人  好吗
and there's someone I wanna introduce you to, okay?
本·戴米奥少校  十一军特种部队队长
Major Ben Daimio, head of Special Ops for M-11.
-十一军  -这是我儿子
- M-11? - My son.
我以为你们在战后就解散了
I thought you guys disbanded after the war.
我以为我们应该
And I thought we were supposed to be
打击怪物  而不是与怪物共事
fighting monsters, not working with them.
你管谁叫怪物呢  哥们
Who you calling monster, pal?
你最近照镜子了吗  疤面煞星
You look in the mirror recently, Scarface?
-这是在玩幽默吗  -也许吧
- Is that meant to be humor? - Maybe.
我的心理医生确实说
My therapist does say that
我依靠笑话寻求正常化
I rely on jokes as a way to normalize.
正常化  是的  祝你好运
Normalize, right. Good luck with that.
很高兴见到你们俩相处融洽
So glad to see you two are getting along.
因为是在英国领土  所以这是一次联合行动
Since this is on British soil, it'll be a joint operation.
拜托  我不用任何帮助就能把俄赛里斯会社
Please, I don't need any help kicking the dentures
打得满地找牙好吗  我能行
out of the Osiris Club, all right? I got this.
不  这比你了解的还要严重
No, this is bigger than you know.
圣赛巴斯蒂安修道院遭到袭击
St. Sebastian's has been attacked
一件古物被盗
and a relic was stolen.
据称是妮缪之棺的其中一具
Thought to be one of the Nimue Caskets.
妮什么
Nim-who?
薇薇安·妮缪
Vivienne Nimue.
也被称为血皇后
Also known as the Blood Queen.
公元五世纪的一位永生不死的女巫
An immortal fifth century sorceress.
她的其中一项能力就是
Amongst her powers, she has a plague
差点毁灭英国的瘟疫
that almost wiped Britain off the map.
而这一次可能毁灭全世界
And this time it could be the world.
亚瑟王亲自收拾了那个怪物
King Arthur himself took care of that monster.
他用王者之剑肢解了她
He used Excalibur to dismember her,
然后把尸块锁在了棺材中
then locked the pieces in caskets
并将棺材藏在了全国的各个角落
and hid them throughout the country.
刮目相看  少校
Very impressive, Major.
俄赛里斯会社在三十年代发现了其中一具
The Osiris Club discovered one in the '30s
把它作为他们的永久收藏
and kept it as part of their permanent collection.
好极了  那我们回俄赛里斯会社
Great. So we go back to the Osiris Club,
找到这个棺材
we find this casket,
搞清楚到底是谁想把血皇后的碎尸
we figure out whoever's trying to Humpty Dumpty
重新拼起来
this Blood Queen back together
顺便对会社进行报复
and we get a little payback while we're at it.
报复  这不是为了复仇
Payback? This isn't about revenge.
对我来说就是
For me, it is.
一旦棺材安全了
Once the casket is secure,
你就要乘第一班飞机离开
you'll be on the first flight out.
防御局可以把你关回你的回笼子里
The Bureau can put you back in your cage.
我的笼子  我的笼子
My cage? My cage!
我会特别要求你来打扫我的锯角屑
I'm gonna ask specifically that you clean my sawdust.
等不及看你闻恶魔的屎了  哥们
Can't wait till you smell demon shit, pal!
他们告诉我你是负责人
They tell me you're the man in charge.
-这是什么  -索赔你们造成的破坏
- What's this? - A bill for damages.
破坏索赔
一百万英镑
一百万英镑  就为几扇打破的窗户
A million pounds? For a few broken windows?
你得考虑到造成的情感创伤
You've gotta factor in the emotional trauma.
不好意思  你是谁来着
I'm sorry, who are you again?
我是救了地狱男爵的女孩  你又是谁
I'm the girl who saved Hellboy. Who the hell are you?
是啊  对了  我想谢谢你救我
Yeah, I wanted to thank you for that, by the way.
所以她是你的保镖吗
So, she's what, your bodyguard?
说得没错  我们出发吧
Fucking right I am. So let's go.
这是军事行动  不是狂欢节的助兴节目
This is a military operation! Not a carnival sideshow.
爱丽丝是我唯一信任的人  好吗
Alice is the only person that I trust, all right?
所以如果你想让我去
So, you want me,
她就得跟着一起
she comes with.
给
Here.
你的新玩具
Your new toy.
做你该做的事
Do what you have to do.
我要回总部
I'm going back to HQ
想办法定位血皇后的其余尸块
and try to locate the rest of the Blood Queen.
祝你们好运
Good luck, hmm?
教授  这女孩怎么办
Professor. What about the girl?
爱丽丝  她是个强大的灵媒
Alice? She's a powerful spirit medium.
带上她一起  我们需要所有的帮手
Take her with you. We need all the help we can get.
好了  这里完事了  我们出发
All right, we're done here! Let's move it out!
你不打算打开看看吗
Well, aren't you gonna open it?
厉害了
That's mega.
他大概是在过度补偿
He's probably overcompensating
因为他不是我亲爸
'cause he's not my real dad.
这个礼物不得了
That's some present.
有些爸爸给孩子买乐高
Some dads get their kids LEGOs.
怎么了
What's wrong?
通灵偏头痛
Psychic migraine.
就像是我大脑里发生了车祸
It's like a car crash in my head.
这里发生了可怕的事
Something terrible happened here.
待在这里  不要动
Stay here. Don't move.
天啊
Oh, God.
-停  按我的指令行动  -什么
- Hold. Move on my command. - What?
我们能进去了吗
Can we go in now?
天啊  救救他  你们没听见他在尖叫吗
For fuck's sake, help him! Can't you hear him screaming?
爱丽丝
Alice.
那是什么声音
What is that sound?
是哈顿夫人
It's Lady Hatton.
你之前告诉我们的那个灵媒
The psychic you were telling us about?
显然  她这个灵媒不够灵
Clearly, she wasn't psychic enough.
爱丽丝  有什么感应吗
Alice, picking up anything?
她的灵魂还在这里
Her spirit's still with us.
你能和她交流吗
You think you can make contact?
搞清楚这里发生了什么
Figure out what the hell happened here?
也许你应该离开  少校
You might wanna leave, Major.
这种事可算不上愉快
This kind of thing isn't pretty.
错过所有的乐趣吗  绝对不可能
And miss all the fun? Not a chance.
哈顿夫人  你能听到我的声音吗
Lady Hatton, can you hear me?
哈顿夫人
Lady Hatton...
见鬼了
Well, I'll be fucked.
妮缪  她回来了
Nimue, she has returned.
嗯  这个我们知道
Yeah, we know that.
这就是俄赛里斯会社想杀我的原因吗
Is that why Osiris tried to kill me?
人类会堕入她的黑暗
Man will fall to her darkness.
黑暗的子民
Those who call the shadows home
将再度崛起
will rise again.
好吧
Okay.
我想要更具体更切实的预言
I'd appreciate a prophecy with smaller and more relatable stakes.
绝不能让皇后找到国王
The Queen must never find a king!
当妮缪再次完整之时
When Nimue is whole again,
你真正的命运就将揭晓
then your true destiny will be revealed.
这是我所见到的  只有到那时...
This I have seen. Only then will...
只有到那时会怎样
Only then will what?
你正说到精彩的部分
You're just getting to the good part!
它还在这里
It's... It's still here!
-你还好吗  -不好
- Are you all right? - No.
一个女人刚从我嘴里钻出来了
A lady just came out of my fucking mouth!
你陪着她
Stay with her.
操
Fuck!
我认识你
I know you.
那是条胳膊吗
Is that an arm?
快他妈放开我
Fucking let me go!
恶心死了
That's disgusting!
你妈难道没教过你
Didn't your mother ever tell you
不要跟死物打交道吗
you shouldn't play with dead things!
皇后陛下  救救我  我还没准备好
My Queen, help me! I'm not ready yet!
皇后陛下
My Queen!
真迷人
Fascinating.
我从没见过像你这样的生物
Never have I seen a creature quite like you.
妮缪
Nimue.
如此强大的力量  如此辉煌的潜力
Such power, such glorious potential.
我们没有理由成为敌人
There is no reason for us to be enemies,
我们可以一起
when we can be
成就更多
so much more.
他们害怕我们  他们称我们为怪物
They fear us. They call us monsters.
我们渴望着同一天
We yearn for the same day,
那一天我们不再被辱骂  而是被称颂为英雄
when we are not reviled but lauded as heroes.
一粒粒种子
Seed by seed,
一棵棵树木  一块块石头
tree by tree, stone by stone,
我们将一起重新种植伊甸园
we'll replant Eden together.
接下来会发生什么
What happens next,
只有命运才能决定
only the fates decide.
地狱男爵
Hellboy!
你他妈的混账
You fucking prick!
没打中  不是吗
I missed, didn't I?
告诉我你抓住那个混蛋了
Tell me you got the bastard.
我们追了  那个该死的跑得太快了
We pursued. The damn thing was just too fast.
我们连它的真面目都没看清
We didn't even get a proper look at it.
那个丑陋的猪脸贱货
That ugly pig-faced son of a bitch.
但是你看到了  对不对
But you did, didn't you?
你知道这是怎么回事
You know what's going on here,
所以我强烈建议你现在就交待
so I strongly suggest you start talking.
是棕精灵
It was the Gruagach.
-什么  -你确定吗
- The what? - Are you sure?
嗯  我绝不会忘记那么一张脸
Yeah. I'd never forget a face like that.
棕精灵是什么
What's a Gruagach?
我们多年前曾经有一面之缘
We first crossed paths years ago.
爱丽丝当时还是个婴儿
Alice was just a baby at the time,
而精灵喜欢偷婴儿
and fairies loved to steal babies.
我们简直像是活在一个
It's like living in a nightmare
永远醒不来的噩梦里
we can't wake up from.
天知道为什么
Who knows why,
但是当他们设法偷到一个孩子后
but when they do manage to get their hands on one,
他们会留下一个换生灵来冒充人类
they leave a changeling in its place to pass for human.
她看上去是一样的  但是
She looks the same, but...
我解释不了
I can't explain it.
这不是我的女儿
That's not my daughter.
看看你
Look at you.
爱丽丝  你真是最可爱的小宝贝
Alice, aren't you the cutest little baby?
你的妈妈和爸爸...
Your mom and your dad are, uh,
担心你最近举止有点奇怪
well, worried that you've been acting strange.
没关系  地狱男爵叔叔来了
It's okay. Uncle Hellboy is here.
他正好有个绝招
And he's got just the thing for that.
嗯  我也是这么想的  你这个小混蛋
Yeah, that's what I thought, you little bastard!
天哪  你在做什么
Jesus! What are you doing?
铁  他们讨厌铁
Iron. They hate the stuff.
放开我
Let me go!
放开我  这是虐待儿童
Let me go! Ahh! This is child abuse!
我是个小宝宝  你这大个子混账
I'm a little baby, you big fuck!
真恶心  那是什么
It's disgusting! What is that thing?
抓不到
Didn't get!
滚开
Fuck off!
疼  疼  我保证  我保证
It hurts! It hurts! I promise! I promise!
精灵会把她送回来的
The fairies will return her!
我发誓  快他妈放开我
I swear! Just fucking let me go!
我也想相信你的话
Yeah, I'd love to take your word for it.
但你知道吗
But you know what?
有个问题  那就是我不傻
There's one problem, I'm just not stupid!
傻逼
Twat!
你这个狡诈的小混蛋
You slippery little bastard!
听着
Listen!
你最好赶紧把他们的孩子送回来
You better bring these people back their baby
否则我就亲自去接她
or I'm coming to get her myself!
然后你和你的精灵小伙伴
And then you and your fairy friends
就有得后悔了
are gonna be sorry!
爱丽丝镜中世界奇遇记
刘易斯·卡罗尔
总算来了
About goddamn time.
爱丽丝
Alice!
天哪  她回来了
Oh, my God. She's back.
最好是新换的尿布
This better be a clean diaper,
否则我会去找你的
or I'm coming after you!
小爱丽丝
Wee Alice.
我不可能永远躲着他
Guess I couldn't avoid him forever.
命运总是有办法
Destiny always has a way
让事情回到原点
of bringing things full circle.
命运
Destiny.
只不过是"巧合"的愚蠢解释
Stupid word for "coincidence."
别说命运的坏话  她是个有仇必报的贱人
Don't talk shit about fate. She's a vindictive bitch.
我们背负着我们血统中的每一个罪恶
We carry every sin committed in our bloodlines.
血皇后也是这么说的
Blood Queen said pretty much the same thing.
这一切是为了什么
So, that's what this is all about?
你之前惹过什么精灵之类的蠢货
Some fairy tale wanker you pissed off
要来找你寻仇了
is now looking for revenge?
而且他正在利用血皇后来达成目的
And he's now using the Blood Queen to get it.
我说不好  或许是她在利用他
I don't know about that. Maybe she's using him.
怎么说
And how's that?
那个叫亚瑟的
This Arthur comes along,
把她砍碎了
chops her up into little pieces,
装在箱子里埋了
buries her in boxes?
也许她只是想让怪物们走出阴影
Maybe she just wants monsters to come out
重新生活呢
from the shadows and live again.
棒极了  这样她就又有灭绝人类的机会了
Great, so she gets another shot at wiping out mankind.
我们不了解她  至少不确定
We don't know that about her. Not for sure.
集合我们的人  我要带他们回伦敦总部
Collect our men. I'm taking them back to London HQ.
夜晚  秘密的忠实守护者
O night, faithful preserver of mysteries.
还有明亮的星辰与月亮
And ye bright stars and moon.
继承了仇恨之日的火焰
Succeed the fires of hateful day.
小心点  你们这些渣滓
Careful, you slags!
比起1500年来
The pain is fleeting
被囚于箱子的折磨  这痛苦不算什么
compared to 1,500 years locked in a box.
我活着只是为了服侍您  皇后陛下
I only live to serve, my Queen.
你服侍我的唯一目的就是
You only serve to get your revenge
向地狱男爵复仇
against this Hellboy.
他对你来说为何如此重要
Why is he so important to you?
他用铁烙伤我
He burnt me with iron
诅咒我永世蒙受耻辱
and cursed me to a world of shame.
我本来可以做个人的
I could've been a person.
而不是这种可悲徘徊的东西
Not this wasted, wandering thing.
我本来可以享受真正的生活
I could've had a real life,
充满了光明和幸福
filled with light and happiness.
地狱男爵剥夺了这个权力
Hellboy stole that from me.
可怜的东西
Poor creature.
复仇的欲望令我们被愤怒蒙蔽了双眼
Lust for vengeance has made us both blind with rage.
妮缪  女巫皇后
Nimue, Queen of Witches.
妮缪还活着
Nimue who lives.
妮缪永生不死
Nimue, who can never die.
但现在
But now,
我看到面前出现了一条新的道路
I see a new path laid out before me,
一条通向更大荣耀的道路
one that would lead to far greater glory.
-你的地狱男爵是关键  -地狱男爵  但是...
- And your Hellboy is the key. - Hellboy? But...
我们这是要做什么  我不明白
Where are we going with this? I don't... I don't understand.
你会明白的
You will.
但首先
But first,
我们必须完成一个最终任务
we must complete one final task.
-炸鱼薯条店  -我们到了
- Fish 'n chips shop? - We're here.
鳕鱼冲击
炸鱼薯条
就是这里吗
This is it?
你指望会有个标志写着"秘密总部"吗
Were you expecting a sign that says "Secret Headquarters"?
来吧
Come on.
哈克夫人
Mrs. Harker.
你好
Hello.
我还以为外面就够难闻了呢
I thought it smelled bad on the outside.
接下来交给你们两个吧  我要走了
I'll let you two take it from here. I'm leaving.
而你  哪也不许去
And you, don't go anywhere.
我最不需要的就是一个怪人
Last thing I need is some freak
在附近闲晃吓到当地人
wandering around scaring the locals.
他要去哪儿
Where's he going?
我们不是要拯救世界吗
Haven't we got to be saving the world or something?
他是个混蛋
He's an asshole.
喂
Oi.
我要看证件  亲爱的
I need some ID, love.
你认真的吗
Are you serious?
恐怕规矩就是规矩
Rules are rules, I'm afraid.
现在炼狱和地狱我都去过了
Now I've been to purgatory and hell.
这是个老防空洞
It was an old bomb shelter
战后重新翻修的
that was refurbished after the war.
翻修  你管这个叫翻修吗
Refurbished? You call this refurbished?
太好了  你来了
Good, you're here!
这是我们目前掌握的有关妮缪的信息
This is all we got on Nimue so far.
我们没事  感谢你的关心
We're fine. Thank you for asking.
你在俄赛里斯会社的朋友可就不太好了
Your friends at Osiris, not so much.
每个故事都不一样
No two stories are alike,
但一切似乎都表明
but everything seems to suggest
除非她完全复原
she won't get her full powers
否则她无法获得全部的力量
until she's completely restored.
你听见了吗  你的朋友都死了
Did you hear me? All your friends are dead!
如果我们不找到她
And there'll be a lot more dead
还会有更多人死去
if we don't find her.
所以或许你们俩可以看看书
So perhaps you two would like to grab a book,
做点研究
do some research,
想办法找出她在哪里
maybe find out where she is,
这样我们就能在她灭了我们之前灭了她
so we can bury her before she buries us.
真好  有作业
Great. Homework.
怪不得戴米奥溜了
No wonder Daimio took off.
枪炮匠
戴米奥探员  十一军  货备好了吗
Agent Daimio, M-11. Is the package ready?
快好了  长官
Sir, almost.
你确定这能管用吗
You're sure this is going to work?
已经有很多人试过杀他了
A lot of people have tried to kill him already.
他们没用过这样的东西
Not with something like this they didn't.
这是用犹大的银币
It's cast from Judas Silver
混合圣多米尼克的血
mixed with the blood of Saint Dominic,
并受过圣父祝福的武器
blessed by the Holy Father himself.
我向你保证  一定管用
It will work, I assure you.
假设你真的用得上
Assuming you've actually got to use it.
我是说  谁能说这家伙不诚实呢
I mean, who's to say this bloke's not on the level?
你知道我当兵前是做什么的吗
Do you know what I did before joining the service?
保险精算师
I was an actuary.
我根据一系列
I assessed risk
复杂的数学方程式来评估风险
based on a series of complex mathematical equations.
你看  人会说谎  但数字不会
You see, people lie, but numbers don't.
在我看来  地狱男爵有所隐瞒
And from where I stand, Hellboy doesn't add up.
他体内的怪物是无法否认的
The monster inside him cannot be denied.
不是针对个人  只是数学而已
It's not personal, it's just maths.
所以没错  不能让他活下去
So, yeah, can't see letting him live.
确保一击致命  要么心脏要么大脑
Make sure it's a kill shot. Either the heart or the brain.
那就心脏吧
The heart it is.
地狱男爵的大脑太小难以瞄准
Hellboy's brain is too small a target.
这本书上怎么这么多字
Why does this book have so many words?
假设我们找到妮缪了  假设找到她了
Let's say we find Nimue, huh? Let's say we find her.
然后呢
Then what?
你要用正义的愤怒和强力的拳头
Well, with a righteous fury and a mighty fist,
将她打倒
you'll smite her down.
好了  拜托  地狱男爵
Now, come on, Hellboy,
把你的脚从丘吉尔的桌子上拿下来  好吗
take your feet off Churchill's desk, will you?
温斯顿·丘吉尔爵士
牛逼
Wicked.
然后呢
Then what?
然后确保她死透  不会卷土重来
Then we make sure she doesn't come back for the sequel.
然后呢
Then what?
然后世界会照常运转
Then the world will keep on spinning
我们就可以再喝杯茶了
and we'll have another cup of tea.
然后...
And then...
呢
what?
你到底在说什么
What are you on about?
回答问题就行了
Just answer the question.
然后呢
And then what?
我们去找下一个敌人  这是我们的工作
Well, we fight our next foe. It's what we do.
-然后呢  -各位
- And then what? - Guys.
然后...呢
And then... what?
你有话要说  就说出来
You have something to say, say it.
你的道德高地是建立在一堆狗屎上的
Your moral high ground is founded on a pile of bullshit.
这里是超自然调查防御局
This is the B.P.R.D.
我们是沙子上的线[底线]We're the line in the sand.
沙子就是这样的
That's the thing about sand,
你可以再画一条线
you can always draw another line.
-各位  -要不是有我们
- Guys! - If we weren't here,
这里早就变成撒旦的度假屋了
this would be Satan's holiday home.
要是人类不那么热衷于
You know, maybe if humans weren't so keen
杀女巫和恶魔之类的
on killing witches and demons and such,
女巫和魔鬼之类的
the witches and demons and such
就不会那么热衷于杀人类
wouldn't be so keen on killing humans.
这是胡搅蛮缠  你心知肚明
That's a false equivalence and you know it.
肯定还有别的办法
There's gotta be another way.
我们面临的每一个威胁的答案
The answer to every threat we face
不可能是消灭
cannot be annihilation.
肯定存在一个怪物
There's gotta be a world where monsters
不用躲在阴影里的世界
don't have to hide in the shadows,
他们不必生活在恐惧之中  怪物可以...
where they don't have to live in fear. Where monsters...
她影响到你了吗  妮缪
Has she got to you? Nimue,
她用花言巧语和挺拔的胸部
she got to you with her perfumed words
打动你了吗
and her perky breasts?
太蠢了
So stupid!
我不是在说她
I'm not even talking about her!
那你是在说谁
Then who?
我们面临世上所有的神秘和超自然威胁
We face every mystical and metaphysical threat there is,
但你还是收养了我  为什么
and yet you take me in. Why?
你是被派去杀我的
You were sent to kill me.
是什么改变了你的想法
What changed your mind?
你
You did.
十岁生日你送了我一把枪
You gave me a gun on my tenth birthday!
你派我去威尔顿根森林
You sent me into the Wildungen forest
狩猎一群野山巨怪
to hunt a pack of wild hill trolls!
又来了
Here we go again.
对  我们没玩过蛇梯棋
No, we didn't play Snakes and Ladders.
我们没玩过钓鱼游戏
We didn't play Go Fish.
我没教过你踢足球或打棒球
I didn't coach you in football or baseball.
你把我变成了该死的武器
You made me a goddamn weapon.
我只是想帮助你成为最好的你
I just wanted to help you become the best you.
如果你真的爱我
If you, uh, loved me,
也许你早该和你那些想置我于死地的
maybe you could talk to some of your human friends
人类朋友谈谈
that would want to see me dead,
而不是让我去
rather than unleashing me
屠杀我的兄弟姐妹
to slaughter my brothers and sisters!
干嘛
What?
教养有方
Just solid parenting.
该死的人类
Goddamn humans.
上楼
Going up.
下楼
Going down.
我按的上楼
I pushed up!
下楼
Going down.
-上楼  -下楼
- Up! - Going down.
搞什么
What the fuck?
-上楼  上楼  上楼  -下楼  下楼  下楼
- Up! Up! Up! Up! - Down. Down. Down. Down.
下楼  下楼  下楼
Down. Down. Down.
下楼
Going down.
地下一层
Lower ground.
雅佳婆婆
Baba Yaga.
婆婆  雅佳婆婆
Baba? Baba Yaga!
省省吧
Cut the crap.
我知道你在
I know you're here.
你为什么召唤我
Why'd you summon me?
你想玩游戏是吧
You wanna play games, huh?
这样吧  我们来玩骰子游戏
Tell you what, let's break out the Yahtzee.
其它的我不感兴趣
Otherwise, I'm not interested.
我感受到了你的饥饿
I felt your hunger,
我为你准备了盛宴
and I have prepared a feast for you.
你可真漂亮
Don't you look lovely.
大多数人认为我丑陋无比  独眼的老巫婆
Most think me grotesque. An old hag with one eye.
不  我不这么认为
No, not me.
因为是你让我变成这样的
Probably because you did this to me!
我记得你试图把斯大林的
I recall you trying to raise
鬼魂从墓地里召唤出来
Stalin's ghost from the Necropolis.
我总得做点什么来阻止你
I had to do something to stop you.
所以你打瞎我的眼睛
So you shot out my eye
把我关进这个监狱
and put me in this prison.
我觉得把你放逐到邻近的空间
You know, I thought that banishing you to an adjacent dimension was,
挺聪明的
kinda clever.
过来  坐下
Come. Sit.
吃吧
Eat.
对两个人来说  真是桌宴席
Yeah. Quite a spread for just two people.
我们庆祝她的归来
We celebrate her return.
妮缪
Nimue?
你为她的正义喝彩是正确的
You are correct to applaud her righteousness.
在她的世界里  你会被奉为英雄
In her world, you will be hailed a hero!
他们会为你建造两千英尺高的雕像
They will build statues of you, 2,000 feet high!
用你敌人的骨头打造而成
Made from the bones of your enemies.
那需要一大堆骨头
That'd take a shit-ton of bones.
晚餐吃什么
What is for dinner?
这是个小孩吗
Is that a child?
人类的小孩而已
It's just a human child.
吃吧
Eat.
天哪
Oh, God!
笨手笨脚  不好意思  我得走了
So clumsy. Sorry about that. I gotta go.
得去复活现场
Gotta be there for that resurrection.
肯定比披头士还带劲
Gonna be better than The Beatles!
我可以帮你
I can help you.
你可以  不是吗
You can, can't you?
你知道妮缪在哪儿  不是吗
You know where Nimue is, don't you?
多漂亮的眼睛
Such nice eyes.
跟尿一样黄
Yellow as piss.
我最爱的颜色
My favorite color.
我想要一个来代替你从我这夺走的眼睛
I want one to replace what you took from me.
那是不可能的  姐妹
That's not gonna happen, sister.
你的时间不多了  恶魔
Your time is running out, demon.
一旦妮缪完成复活
Once Nimue's resurrection is complete,
她的瘟疫会剥去人们身体上的肉
her plague will strip the flesh from bodies.
好吧  行  给你
All right, fine, take it.
先告诉我去哪找妮缪
Just tell me where to find Nimue first.
这是一项神圣的交易
This is a sacred bargain.
一旦达成  就不能打破
Once made, it cannot be broken.
怎么  你想要书面的吗
What, do you want it in writing?
不需要
No need.
我们用吻达成交易
Let's seal it with a kiss.
你的舌头上怎么有毛
How do you have hair on your tongue?
去彭德尔山
Go to Pendle Hill.
她需要回收她的血液
She will need to reclaim her blood
才能恢复她的力量
in order to restore her power.
你必须在午夜前赶到
You only have until midnight.
哪一只好呢  右眼
Which shall it be, the right
还是左眼
or the left?
好了  这会非常疼
Now, this will hurt a lot.
-你发过誓的  -你会得到你的眼睛
- You swore! - You'll get your eye.
等我用完就给你
Soon as I'm done with it.
我们没明确时间范围
We never specified a time frame.
应该说得更具体些的
Should've been more specific.
你一直在吃小孩
You've been eating children!
[咒语]
滚  带走你的眼睛
Go! Take your eyes
继续用一段时间
and have them for a while.
但是你骗我  我要诅咒你
But cheat me and here's my curse,
你有两只眼睛
that you have two eyes
用来看你在这世上最爱的东西
to see the thing you love most in the world
痛苦地死去
suffer and die!
你是不打算用门了吗
So, are you just not using doors anymore?
别吊我们胃口
Don't keep us in suspense.
我刚刚去见雅佳婆婆了
I just had a visit from Baba Yaga.
血皇后在彭德尔山
The Blood Queen's in Pendle Hill.
我们时间紧迫
We're on a clock!
很高兴看到你理顺了轻重缓急
Glad to see you've straightened your priorities out.
我不听你的命令  老头
I'm not taking orders from you, old man!
我只是在沙子上画我自己的线
I'm just drawing my own line in the sand!
谁来帮我拿个薄荷糖
Somebody, please, get me a mint!
好久不见  老朋友
It has been a long time, old friend.
太变态了
This is sick.
你知道他们在彭德尔山对那些女巫做了什么吗
Do you know what they did to the witches at Pendle Hill?
他们割掉她们的舌头  拿去喂蛆
They cut off their tongues, fed them to maggots
然后当场把她们活埋了
and buried them alive right there on the spot.
不要相信你在网上看到的一切
Don't believe everything you read on the Internet.
我说错什么了吗
What did I say?
清除世界上的邪恶是脏活
Ridding the world of evil is a dirty business.
你和怪物到底有什么渊源
What's with you and monsters, anyway?
小时候有怪物非礼过你吗
One of them touch you funny as a kid?
我这辈子见过太多变态的事情了
I've been seeing freaky shit my whole life,
如果说教会了我什么的话
and if it's taught me anything,
那就是仇恨隐藏在最正直的面孔之后
it's that hate hides behind the most righteous faces.
你真的要跟我讲面孔的事情吗
Are you seriously gonna lecture me about faces?
也许你认为这些伤疤是我刮胡子弄出来的
Maybe you think I got these scars from shaving.
发生了什么  我会一直问下去的
What happened? I'm not gonna stop asking.
还不如直接告诉我
You might as well tell me.
那时我的部队在伯利兹进行训练演习
My unit was on a training exercise in Belize.
当地的一个部落长老来找我们求助
One of the local tribal elders came to us asking for help.
他们的村庄遭到一个食人兽的袭击
Their village was under attack by a man-eater.
它会在晚上出现  抓走它的猎物
It would come at night, carry off its prey.
主要是男人  但有时是妇女和儿童
Mostly men, but sometimes it was women and children, too.
野蛮  聪明
Savage. Smart.
毫无悔意
Totally without remorse.
在我们狩猎它的过程中
All the while that we were hunting it,
实际上是它在狩猎我们
in reality, it was hunting us.
我是唯一的幸存者
I was the only survivor.
我很遗憾
I'm so sorry.
我们接近目标了
We're coming up on target.
我们不可能在那座山上着陆
There's no way we can land on that hill.
我会尽可能靠近
I'll get us up as close as I can.
皇后  给您
Here you go, Queen.
您很快就会恢复成原来的自己
You'll be back to feeling your amazing old self in no time.
我的生命之血支撑着你
My life blood sustains you...
但现在我必须取回属于我的东西
But now I must reclaim what is mine.
其他人马上就到了
The others will be here soon.
那地狱男爵呢
What about Hellboy?
如果他来了  我准备了一个小惊喜
If he comes, I have a little surprise in store.
快点  快到午夜了
Come on, it's almost midnight!
时间不多了
Time's running out.
等等  等一下
Wait! Wait! Just wait!
我不是恶魔也不是士兵  我他妈累死了
I'm not a demon or a soldier. I'm fucking knackered.
-稍微休息一下  -好吧
- Just give us a sec. - All right.
我来帮你...
Let me give you...
一把
a hand!
这个国家的死人就不能老实待在地下吗
Won't anything in this country stay buried!
现在不行
Not now!
地狱男爵  快到午夜了
Hellboy! It's almost midnight.
去找血皇后  这里交给我们
Go find the Blood Queen. We can handle this.
如果你不阻止她  她就会释放瘟疫
She'll spread her plague if you don't stop her!
没时间了  快去
There's no time! Go!
爱丽丝  我不会离开你的
Alice, I'm not leaving you.
快去  阻止妮缪
Go! Stop Nimue!
我没子弹了  躲在我身后
I'm out. Stay behind me!
我他妈还能去哪儿
Where the fuck else am I gonna go?
好球
Goal!
[咒语]
终于
At last...
我重生了
I am reborn.
是的  您气色不错  陛下
Yeah, you're looking good, Your Majesty.
她是城堡的皇后
She's the queen of the castle.
他们来了  皇后陛下
They're here, my Queen.
他们从黑暗中出来
They've come from out of the darkness
庆祝您的回归
to celebrate your return.
不用再点头哈腰了  我亲爱的子民
No more bowing and scraping, my beloveds.
那不是我想要的
That is not what I want.
我想要一支大军
I want an army,
长期隐藏于人类的视线之外
long hidden from the eyes of man.
我想要被遗忘的人走出黑暗
I want the forgotten people out of the dark!
那些生活在尘土中的人
Those who have lived in dust,
那些啃食干骨头  梦见鲜血的人
who have gnawed on dry bones while dreaming of blood!
那就是我想要的  给我一支这样的军队
That is what I want. Give me an army like that
我们会让白天的世界哭泣
and we will make the daytime world weep!
不要像老鼠一样蜷缩在那里
Well, don't just cower there like mice.
上前来
Step forth.
亲爱的姐妹们
Dear sisters.
你们真好  藏了那么多年
How kind of you to grace me with your presence
现在过来捧场
after hiding all these years.
求求您  妮缪  仁慈对待我和姐妹们
Please, Nimue, for me and my sisters, have mercy.
戈内达  你对我仁慈过吗
Ganeida, did you show me mercy?
当亚瑟把我砍碎
When Arthur cut me to pieces
活埋我的时候
and buried me alive,
你的仁慈在哪里
where was your mercy then?
-不要  求求您  -看看你
- Don't, I beg you! - Look at you.
像动物一样卑躬屈膝
Groveling like an animal.
别担心  戈内达  我不会杀你的
Don't worry, Ganeida, I won't kill you.
但你必须先为我做件事
But you must do something for me first
来证明你新发现的忠诚
to prove your newfound loyalty.
带地狱男爵去见那个能指引他命运的人
Take Hellboy to the one who can show him his destiny.
不好意思  我打断你们了吗
Sorry! Did I interrupt?
地狱男爵  你个混蛋
Hellboy, you bastard!
我希望我没迟到
I hope I'm not late to the party!
你来得正是时候
You've arrived just in time.
数量太多了
There's too many.
放开他
Get off him!
你后面
Behind you!
你从哪儿学来的
Where'd you learn how to do that?
我不知道  自从我被精灵带走
I don't know. Ever since the fairies took me,
我就能做一些奇怪的事
I've been able to do some weird shit.
躲在我身后
Stay behind me.
我还能去哪儿
Where else am I gonna go?
带我们离开这里
Get us out of here!
知道什么时候该等待
Know when to wait.
现在没那么好笑了  是吧
Not so fucking funny now, eh?
皇后陛下  恢复我的力量  让我干掉他
My Queen, restore me now! Let me finish him!
现在还不行
Not just yet.
但是你发过誓...
But you swore...
管好你的舌头  猪头
Mind your tongue, pig.
快走
Move it.
进去
Get in.
你想去哪儿
Where do you think you're going?
去孕育一个新的世界
To give birth to a new world!
是啊  通过杀害许多无辜的人
Yeah, by killing a lot of innocent people!
为什么你要为那些憎恨和恐惧你的人而战
Why do you fight for those who hate and fear you?
见到你之前  我只想要复仇
All I wanted was revenge, until I saw you.
但你可以迎来世界末日
You can usher in the apocalypse.
灰烬中将诞生新的伊甸园
Out of the ashes, a new Eden will emerge.
抛下这些脆弱可怜的人类
Leave these frail, pathetic humans behind.
做我的国王  以你的真实身份接受爱戴
Be my king. And be revered for who you really are.
我们属于彼此  你和我
We belong together, you and I.
确实如此  但是行不通的  你知道
We do! But it's not gonna work, you know,
因为我是摩羯座  而你是他妈疯子座
'cause I'm a Capricorn and you're fucking nuts!
你的体内沉睡着恶魔  我会唤醒它
A demon sleeps inside you, and I will waken it.
地狱男爵  地狱男爵
Hellboy! Hellboy!
即使我必须夺走你所爱过的
Even if I have to take away everything
一切人事物
and everyone you've ever loved.
我来了  孩子
I got you, kid.
恭喜你  血皇后恢复了全部力量
Congratulations, the Blood Queen has all her powers now.
别碰它
Don't touch it!
那只会让它扩散得更快
It'll only make it spread faster.
给你三秒钟时间来弥补
You got three seconds to make this right!
我做不到
I can't.
三
Three.
妮缪的力量太强大了
Nimue's power is too strong.
二
Two.
旧世界有一个人可以帮助你
There is one who can help you from the Old World.
在哪儿
Where?
你不会真要听她的吧
You're not seriously gonna listen to her!
她可能会把我们引入陷阱
She could be leading us straight into a trap!
你可以救你的朋友
You can save your friend.
我们别无选择
We don't have a choice.
去黑鳍山
Go to Black Fin.
在悬崖顶上
High atop the cliffs
岩石中隐藏着一条古老的牧羊道
there's an old goat path hidden in the rocks.
这条路充满危险
The way is treacherous,
但你必须沿着它走到尽头
but you must follow it until you can go no further.
在那  你会在山洞中找到通往地球内部的通道
There, you'll find a passage into the bowels of the Earth, in a cave.
这边  戴米奥
This way, Daimio.
你要找的人就在那里
The one you seek is there.
智者梅林
Merlin the Wise.
国王的巫师  愚者的国王
Wizard to kings, and king of fools.
因为允许亚瑟背叛停战协议
Cursed to live forever buried in a hole
而被诅咒永远活埋在洞里
for allowing Arthur to betray the truce.
你终于要带走我的灵魂了吗
Have you finally come to claim my soul?
我不是死神
That's the other guy.
快点  我的朋友中毒了
Come on! My friend's been poisoned,
有人告诉我们你能帮忙
and we were told that you can help!
我见过这个  这是妮缪干的
I have seen this before. This is Nimue's work.
你不能小瞧这个女巫
You cannot underestimate this witch.
她是邪恶的化身
She is evil incarnate.
如果我们迅速行动  还有机会
There's still a chance if we act quickly.
但作为回报  你必须答应我一件事
But you must promise me something in return.
你要不惜一切代价
That you will do whatever is necessary
摧毁妮缪
to destroy Nimue, no matter the cost.
我他妈保证做到
I can damn well guarantee it.
[咒语]
我们不用担心那东西要去哪吗
Should we be worried about where that's going?
欢迎回来
Welcome back.
新来的是谁
Who's the new guy?
我说了你肯定不信
You wouldn't believe me if I told you.
你为什么这么做
Why did you do that?
让你的朋友休息  他们会没事的
Let your friends rest. They'll be fine.
接下来发生的事你要独自面对
What comes next is for you and you alone.
地狱男爵  你的故事在我耳边低语
Hellboy, your story whispered itself into my ear
我意识到命运对我们两个另有安排
and I realized fate had something else in store for us both.
-好吧  -告诉我
- Okay. - Tell me,
你的时代中还有亚瑟王的传说吗
are there still tales of King Arthur in your time?
他是怎样从石头中拔出剑来
How he drew the sword from the stone?
是的  还有电影
Yeah. Movies, too.
他是个常见的流行文化巨星
He's a regular pop culture phenom.
把手给我
Give me your hand.
人们以为亚瑟的血统随他而去了
People believe that Arthur's lineage died with him,
但那不是真的
but it's not true.
亚瑟有了一个女儿  那个女儿又有了女儿
The bloodline continued when Arthur had a daughter
如此继续  血统就延续下去了
and that daughter had a daughter, and so on.
最后一位是萨拉·贝瑟尼·休斯
Ending with Sarah Bethany Hughes.
她曾在一个山羊形状的
She used to fly to the Sabbath
恶魔的背上飞向安息日
on the back of a demon in the shape of a goat.
然后在1574年的五朔节前夕
And on Walpurgis Night, 1574,
她嫁给了那个恶魔
she married that demon.
就在那天晚上  她被拖下了地狱
That very night she was taken down to hell,
她在那里生下了一个儿子
where she delivered a son,
阿努·恩·罗摩
Anung un Rama.
最后那部分  我之前听到过  那是什么
That last part, I've heard that before. What is that?
是你  阿努·恩·罗摩
It's you... Anung un Rama.
万物毁灭者
Destroyer of all things.
你出生那天被授予的头衔
The title you were given on the day you were born.
所以我母亲是人类
So, my mother was human.
你也是人类  至少一部分是
And so are you. At least in part.
亚瑟之子  王族最后的后裔
Son of Arthur, last of the royal lineage.
他的血脉
Blood of his blood.
注定要成为人类之王
Destined to be king of man.
所以我知道你是
Which is why I know you are
唯一一个能做到必要的事的人
the only one who can do what must be done.
王者之剑  唯一可以对抗妮缪的武器
Excalibur, the one weapon that can stand against Nimue.
在动画里看起来比这大
Looks bigger in the cartoon.
只有亚瑟的真正后裔才能挥动它
Only a true descendant of Arthur can wield it.
地狱男爵  这是你与生俱来的权力  你的命运
It is your birthright, Hellboy, your destiny.
这就是你摧毁血皇后的方法
This is how you will destroy the Blood Queen.
不  你答应过我的
No! You gave me your word!
趁现在还来得及  把剑拔出来
Take the sword before it's too late!
拔出来
Take it!
快拔出来
Take it now!
你个傻瓜
You fool!
我用最后的魔力把王者之剑带到了这里
I used the last of my magic to bring Excalibur here.
现在剑回到了亚瑟身边
Now the sword has returned to Arthur,
唯一配得上它的人
the only man worthy of it.
你本可以阻止她的
You could've stopped her.
至少我不会在这里
At least I won't be here
看着这个世界凋零死亡
to watch the world wither and die.
跑啊  对  快跑
Run! Yeah, go on, run.
你们这些可悲的混蛋
You pathetic bastards.
到目前为止  英国政府
So far, the British government
还没有找到这场正以
has failed to pinpoint the origin of the plague
前所未有的速度蔓延的瘟疫的源头
which is spreading at an unprecedented rate.
首相已官方宣布
The Prime Minister has declared
进入紧急状态
an official state of emergency
并敦促英国公民留在室内
and is urging British citizens to remain indoors
避免与任何可能被感染的人接触
and to avoid contact with anyone who may be infected.
预计伤亡人数将在两小时内达到十万人
Casualties are expected to reach 100,000 within two hours,
突发新闻
致命瘟疫爆发
英国瘟疫将在未来24小时内
with the British plague spreading to the EU
蔓延至欧盟
resulting in massive fatalities
造成大量死亡
over the next 24 hours
并有可能引发全球疫情
and threatening to spark a global epidemic.
听好了  女士们先生们
Listen up, ladies and gentlemen.
情况已经糟到不能更糟了
The shit has gone way beyond the fan.
那里有个来自五世纪的女巫
Out there, there's a fifth century sorceress
和她的猪怪
and her pig monster,
想要毁灭伦敦和整个世界
who want to bring down the curtain on London and the world.
现在请告诉我  他们在哪儿
Now, please tell me where the fuck they are!
我要看证件  亲爱的
I need to see some ID, love.
感染率远远高于最初...
The infection rate is much higher than initially...
你要告诉我们下面发生了什么吗
You gonna tell us what happened down there?
甘道夫去哪儿了
Where's Gandalf?
他死了  他要把剑给我  王者之剑
He's dead. He offered me the sword, Excalibur.
他说那是杀死血皇后的唯一方法
He said it was the only way to kill the Blood Queen.
好吧  剑在哪呢
All right, so where is it?
我没拿剑
I didn't take the sword.
因为如果我拿了  我就是那个
'Cause if I do, I'm the guy who's gonna
开启世界末日的人
bring about the end of the world.
你是那个开启世界末日的人
You're the guy who's going to bring about the end of the world?
少自大了
Get over yourself.
戴米奥
Daimio!
我们有任务要完成
We've got a job to do.
我们得走了
We've got to go.
出什么事了
What's wrong?
血皇后刚刚攻破了超自然调查防御局
The Blood Queen just took out the B.P.R.D.
爸
Dad.
我们会找到你爸爸的  他没死
We'll find your father. He's not dead.
相信我  我会知道的
Trust me, I'd know.
看看这个
Have a look at this.
我在圣保罗大教堂外面
I'm outside St. Paul's Cathedral,
就在那边
and right over there,
圣保罗大教堂大屠杀
数百名武装警察继续与一名
hundreds of armed police continue a shootout
身份不明的袭击者交火
with an unknown assailant.
让开
Get out of the way!
我跟你们是一伙的
I'm on your side!
-抱歉  我的错  -十一军
- Sorry. My bad. - M-11!
任何情况下都不准进入
No one enters under any circumstances!
她在哪儿
Where is she?
爸
Dad!
你好  地狱男爵
Hello, Hellboy.
很抱歉皇后陛下不能亲自来迎接你
Sorry my queen couldn't be here to greet you in person.
这可不是好兆头
That's not a good sign.
他怎么变得这么大
How did he get so fucking big?
地狱男爵  如你所见
Hellboy, as you can see,
她确保了你能受到正式的欢迎
she's made sure you receive a proper fucking welcome.
你不知道我等这一刻等了多久
You've no idea how long I've been waiting for this.
我可以想象
I have some idea!
要知道  我就是那个让小猪仔
You know, I was the guy that sent little piggy squealing
一路尖叫着跑回家的家伙
all the way back home.
找掩护
Take cover!
我要把你的头拧下来
I'll rip your fucking head off!
当心
Look out!
小猪仔  我带来了你的最爱  铁
Little piggy, I brought your favorite! Iron!
这次不管用了
That's not gonna work this time.
我抬不动
It won't budge!
尝尝这个  混蛋
Take that, you fucker!
过来  你...
Come here, you...
该死的浑蛋
Fucking bastard.
离开这里
Get out of here.
我不会就这么扔下你
I'm not just gonna leave you!
快走
Go!
滚开
Fuck off!
看看你  你的脸就像狒狒的屁股
Look at ya. You got a face like a baboon's ass.
乖乖躺在那儿流血  让我把你干掉
Now just lay there and bleed while I finish you off.
是吗
Oh, yeah?
祝你好运  伙计
Good luck with that, pal!
该死的杂种
Fucking mutt.
戴米奥
Daimio?
我们吃烤肉吧
Let's eat some barbecue!
-地狱男爵  -给我这个干什么
- Hellboy!  - What am I supposed to do with that?
即兴发挥
Improvise!
我要砸烂你的脑袋
I'm gonna squash your fucking head now.
-来吧  你个红脸傻逼  -够了
- Here, you red-faced twat! - Enough!
陛下
Your Majesty.
放过他  我的宠物
Let him go, my pet.
我们说好的  我把你拼齐了
We had a deal. I found you.
这一切都是我策划的  我是一切的开始
I set all this in motion! I was the beginning of it all.
而我是终点
And I am the end.
原谅我  我需要有人挑战地狱男爵
Forgive me. I needed someone to challenge Hellboy,
把他逼到绝境
push him to the edge.
但你答应过的
But you promised!
答应恢复你的力量
To make you whole again.
无与伦比的强大
Powerful beyond compare.
在短暂闪耀的时间内
And for one brief, shining moment,
-确实实现了  -这不公平
- you were. - This ain't fair!
你去死  地狱男爵
Fuck you, Hellboy!
嗯  你也去死
Yeah, fuck you back.
好了  该结束了
All right, time to finish this.
但我不想杀你
But I don't want to kill you.
我们不是敌人  我们被命运连结在一起
We are not enemies. We are bound together by fate!
别再说这些废话了  女士
Not this crap again, lady!
有些教训值得重复
Some lessons bear repeating.
想想有多少人一生都在
Just think how many spent their lives
寻找亚瑟的坟墓
searching for Arthur's tomb.
它一直都在这里
It's been right here all along.
拔剑吧  这是你的权力
Go ahead. It's yours by right.
你能感受到  不是吗
You can feel it, can't you?
它在呼唤你
How it calls to you.
搅动你生命的核心
Stirring the thing at the core of your being.
你注定要成为的人
The thing you're destined to be.
拔剑吧
Go ahead, take it.
你想杀我  不是吗
You want to kill me, don't you?
拔剑  拔剑
Pick up the sword. Take it!
不
No!
我不知道你在耍什么把戏
I don't know what your game is here,
但我不玩了
but I'm done playing!
那好
Very well.
爸  爸
Dad! Dad!
别担心我
Don't worry about me.
你做你该做的  干掉这个婊子
You do what you have to do and take out this bitch!
不  妮缪  妮缪  不  放开他  妮缪
No! Nimue! Nimue, no! Let him go, Nimue!
放开他  你想要的是我  来抓我
Let him go! It's me you want! Take me!
你已经在我手上了
I already have you.
你只是还不知道罢了
You just don't know it yet.
不  不  不
No! No! No!
爸
Dad!
Dad?
不  求你别死
No. Please don't go.
不
No!
老天  伙计  你真是一团糟
Jesus Christ, mate. You're a mess.
好吧  至少现在我知道为什么
Well, at least now I know why
你一直表现的像个该死的混蛋了
you've been acting like such a fucking dick.
我需要你立刻振作起来
I need you to pull it together now!
他需要我们的帮助
He needs our help.
别哭了
Save your tears.
比起我为全人类准备的下场
His death is a mercy compared to
他的死是一种仁慈
what I have in store for the rest of mankind.
都是因为在你有机会使用王者之剑时
All because you were too cowardly to use Excalibur
你太懦弱了
when you had the chance.
你的两个父亲都会以你为耻
Both your fathers would be ashamed!
妮缪
Nimue!
到我这儿来
Come to me.
来
Come.
你太美了
You're so beautiful.
现在你明白了  我们生来就要共同统治
Now you see that we were born to rule together.
亚瑟只是个凡人
Arthur was just a man.
在他手中  王者之剑是死亡的工具
In his hands, Excalibur was an instrument of death.
但在你手中  你可以建立新的世界
But in yours, you can build a new world,
为我们的同类建立更美好的世界
a better world for all our kind.
陛下
My Lord.
住手
Stop!
这不是你  地狱男爵  你不是这样的人
This isn't you, Hellboy. You're better than this.
别听这个老傻瓜的话  这是你命中注定的
Don't listen to this old fool. You were meant for this.
她想利用你
She wants to use you,
扭曲你的本性
make you into something you're not.
所以别再发牢骚了
So stop being a whiny little shit
向她证明她错了
and show her she's wrong.
勇往直前  拥抱你的命运
Go forth and embrace your destiny.
摧毁你的敌人
Destroy your enemies!
没完没了地唠叨抱怨命运
All this bitching and moaning about destiny.
成熟点吧  你是个男人
Grow a pair! You're a man!
而且是个好人  做个好人
And a good one! Act like it.
别让预言告诉你你是谁
Don't let a prophecy tell you who you are.
你自己做决定
You decide for yourself.
他在撒谎
He's lying!
你是世界末日的伟大野兽
You are the great beast of the apocalypse.
这就是真正的你  一直都是
This is the real you! It always has been.
烧尽过去
Burn out the past.
摆脱弱点
Be rid of the weakness.
我的国王
My King.
还没结束
This isn't over!
我们注定要在一起
We are destined for one another!
我们会再见面的
We will meet again
在世界末日的最后一天
on the last day of the ending of the world!
女士  别说了  你还剩
Lady, quit while you're...
-一个头  -不
- A head.  - No!
不
No!
你早就知道  对不对
You knew, didn't you?
一直都知道
This whole time.
我体内的这个野兽
This beast inside me.
我内心的本性
My inner nature!
我的命运
My destiny!
你也知道
So did you.
那么多年前你为什么不杀了我
Why didn't you kill me all those years ago?
你有任务
You had a job,
保护世界不受怪物的侵害
to protect the world from monsters!
我从来没有为那晚做的决定后悔过
I have never, ever regretted the decision I made that night.
爸
Dad...
闭嘴听我说  我有话要说
Shut up and listen to me. There's things I need to say.
我尽力做我能做到的最好的父亲
I tried to be the best father I could.
我怎么知道怎么养孩子
What the hell did I know about raising a kid?
我是个杀手  而且很在行
I was a killer, and damn good at it.
有些野兽罪有应得  有些则不是
Some beasts deserved it, some didn't.
但我做了我认为必要的事
But I did what I believed was necessary.
如果我死后有机会变成天使
And if I have any chance of growing wings,
那都是因为你
it's because of you.
你改变了我
You changed me.
你改变了一切
You changed everything.
如果这场看似永无止境的战争有结束的时候
And if there is ever an end in this seemingly forever war,
那将是因为你和你强大的右手
it will be because of you and your strong right hand.
你是人类最好的  也是唯一的希望  孩子
You are mankind's best and only hope, my boy.
求你了  求你别死  我还没准备好
Please. Please don't go. I'm not ready.
不  你准备好了
Oh, yes, you are.
做你的父亲是我做过的最好的决定
Being your father was the best decision I ever made.
我爱你  地狱男爵
I love you, Hellboy.
那是什么
What's that?
一个错误
A mistake.
我喜欢猫
I like cats.
我一直都更喜欢狗
I've always been more of a dog person.
那么  现在你是英格兰国王了
So, you're the king of England now.
-对啊  -好吧  我真没想到
- Yup.  - Well, I didn't see that coming.
六个月后
西伯利亚
好了  我们到了
Okay, yeah, we're here.
有人收到吗  有人...
Does anybody copy? Does any...
没用的废物
Worthless piece of crap!
奥尼斯协会
The Oannes Society.
从太阳神厄里奥皮克兄弟协会中分裂出的团体
他们让俄赛里斯会社看起来像是童子军
They make Osiris look like Cub Scouts.
老天  又一个秘密男孩俱乐部吗
Christ! Another secret boys club?
一群疯子  他们在这里干什么
Bunch of lunatics. What are they doing here?
我们的后援呢
And where's our back-up?
拜托
Come on!
不要这样鬼鬼祟祟地靠近我
Do not sneak up on me like that!
你就不能停止抱怨吗
Don't you ever stop bitching?
很高兴你能加入我们
I'm glad you could join us.
好了  来吧  进入你的战斗模式
Yeah. Okay, come on, let's get your game face on.
这不是像电灯一样能够随意开关的东西
It's not something I can just turn on and off like a light switch.
变形是对痛苦和情感的
The transformation is an electro-chemical reaction
一种电化学反应...
to pain and emotional...
很遗憾地告诉你
I'm sorry to say,
比这个要复杂一点...
it's a bit more complicated than that...
欢迎来到超自然调查防御局
Welcome to the B.P.R.D.
来吧  我们上
Yeah, come on, let's do this.
没人告诉我有着装要求啊
Nobody told me there was a dress code.
各位  看看这个
Guys, check it out.
两栖类人动物
1865年4月14日
"两栖类人动物"
"Icthyo Sapien."
有人知道这是什么意思吗
Anyone know what that means?
鱼人亚伯  地狱男爵的伙伴
地狱男爵
♪ 丹尼小子 ♪
♪ Oh, Danny boy ♪
Danny Boy[爱尔兰民谣]
♪ 笛声在声声呼唤着你 ♪
♪ The pipes The pipes are call... ♪
我是说  没关系的
I mean, it's fine, you know.
崔沃·布鲁姆
父亲
有很多光的地方  阴影是最深的  - 歌德
就好像我们完成了任务
It's like, we got the job done and everything.
我装出开心的样子
I put on a happy face.
但我感觉  我说不好  感觉有点...
But just feel, I don't know, feels kinda...
我同情你  孩子
I feel for you, kid.
教授是个好人
The Professor was a good man.
我靠
Holy crap!
听着
Listen.
你大概经常听人这么说  我不...
You probably get this all the time. And I don't...
我觉得自己这么做很混蛋  你知道吗
I feel like such a jerk doing this, you know?
但其实我是你的头号粉丝
But it's like, I'm actually your biggest fan.
我  我读过你所做过的一切...
I... I... I've read about everything you've done...
-我打断一下  -好
- Let me stop you right there. - Okay.
我猜你想看看热能手套
I suppose you wanna see the claw.
嗯
Yeah.
天啊
Oh, my God!
特别厉害
It's impressive.
可不是吗
You're telling me.
我想你老爸不会想看到
I don't think your old man would wanna
你坐在这里闷闷不乐的
see you sitting around here moping.
-对  你说的大概是对的  -你得回到战斗中去
- No, you're probably right. - Gotta get back in the fight.
-是啊  -战斗还没结束
- Yeah. - It's unfinished business.
-嗯  好  -把我自己害死了
- Yeah, okay. - Got myself killed.
那不是你的错
Well, it wasn't your fault.
-但是听着  -嗯
- But listen. - Yeah.
-大战要来了  -好
- Big one's coming. - Okay.
你赢了一场战斗
You won a battle.
现在你得去战争中大打出手了
Now you gotta go kick ass in the war.
是吗
I do?
好吧
Okay!
行  好吧
All right! Okay!
别废话了  做好准备
Now cut the shit, buckle up,
回到战斗中去
get back in the fight.
我爱你  龙虾队长
I love you, Lobster Johnson!
好吧
Okay.
好了  发生了这事
All right, that happened.
他嘲笑我  我受够了
He mocks me! And I've had enough!
去杀了地狱男爵  把他的眼睛给我
Go! Kill Hellboy and bring me his eye!
你能做到吗
Can you do that?
我能
I can.
如果我做到了呢
And if I do?
我会实现你最大的愿望
I will grant you your greatest wish.
那是什么
And that is?
我会让你终于能死去
I will finally let you die.